shafiq.pk 2011-01-27

# Privacy Policy | shafiq.pk - Latest Technology Updates

## Privacy Policy

shafiq.pk values our fellow bloggers and readers privacy, however for maintaining visitors stats and keeping away the shitty spammers, we need to collect and preserve small piece of visitors information in the form of cookies.

Details of these collected information is described below in [Privacy Policy](http://shafiq.pk/privacy-policy/ "Privacy Policy") section

### Privacy Policy

  * We use different tracking tools to track visitors information. We are using Google Analytics and Ice Rocket Tracker to track visitors information including IP address, Operating System and Web browser etc. We guaranteed you that we do not sharing this sensitive information with any third party. We collect this data just to increase our sites performance so that we can serve you in a better way.
  * shafiq.pk is hosted on bluehost.com but we do not share any information with the host.
  * We are using WordPress which is an open source software written in php. When visitors comment on our site, it stores small piece of data on users computer just to identify when user comes back again. This information is simply a text file and is not in anyway a malware or virus thing.
  * We use third party advertising companies like Google Adsense and Chitika Inc. to serve the ads. These companies may collect your information (This doesn’t include your name, email, address or phone number) about your website browsing behaviors
  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site.
  * Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

### Comments Policy

  * All the comments on shafiq.pk are being moderated by the author for the first time
  * shafiq.pk has full rights to edit, delete and censor the comments however we do not modify the comments.
  * Valid email address is required in order to comment on any article. we do not publish your email on the blog nor shared. Email can be used by the author to privately contact the commenter.
  * This blog is “family friendly” and comments which include offensive or inappropriate language, or considered by the blog owner and administrator to be rude and offensive, will be edited or deleted. Play nice.
